<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gibran Hemani</title>
    <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gibran Hemani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.explodecomputer.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.explodecomputer.com/img/bal.png&#34; alt=&#34;balance&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an Associate Professor in Statistical Genetics at the University of Bristol. My academic interests are in genetics, computational methods, statistical methods for causal inference and decolonisation. I currently hold a Wellcome Trust Sir Henry Dale Fellowship, which focuses on leveraging large scale genetic data to improve causal inference in epidemiological models. I obtained a PhD in quantative genetics at the University of Edinburgh, UK, and then spent two years at the University of Queensland, Australia prior to coming to Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live with my wife and three astonishingly messy creatures (two small children, one dog) in Bristol, UK, and have been here since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site collates my publications, software, current projects and teaching materials. Do get in touch if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in my work, have questions, or perhaps fancy a quick game of chess =]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a full list of publications see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=6fC0BYYAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;google scholar&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;causal-inference&#34;&gt;Causal inference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic variation is abundant across individuals within a population, and it can explain a substantial proportion of the risk of disease and variation in quantitative phenotypes. An interesting thing about genetic variation is that it can be treated like a natural experiment, in which observing the genotype at a relevant locus is akin to observing the outcome of a randomly allocated treatment effect. This is the basis of Mendelian randomisation, a method for inferring causal relationships between phenotypes. Much of my current work focuses on developing statistical and computational methods to improve the scope and reliability of Mendelian randomisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;opengwas&#34;&gt;OpenGWAS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world&amp;rsquo;s largest collection of genome-wide association study (GWAS) summary data. The goal of this project is to systematically harmonise complete GWAS summary datasets against the human genome reference panel in order to enable rapid and robust programmatic analysis of thousands of molecular traits, complex traits and diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gwas.mrcieu.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;https://gwas.mrcieu.ac.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genetics-of-dna-methylation&#34;&gt;Genetics of DNA methylation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNA methylation levels in human blood varies across tissues and between individuals. The goal of GoDMC is to map the genetic factors that drive that variability. We can use these factors as natural experiments, to understand the consequences of perturbations of DNA methylation to human trait and disease variation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://godmc.org.uk/&#34;&gt;http://godmc.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genetics-of-huntingtons-disease&#34;&gt;Genetics of Huntington&amp;rsquo;s disease&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huntington&amp;rsquo;s disease is caused by a well-known expansion of repetitive DNA sequence in the &lt;em&gt;HTT&lt;/em&gt; gene. However, there is substantial variation between individuals with the pathogenic allele in terms of age of onset and symptoms experienced. I work with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chdifoundation.org/&#34;&gt;CHDI foundation&lt;/a&gt; to develop a better understanding of the complex genetic influences on disease progression of Huntington&amp;rsquo;s disease/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statistical-methods-for-covid-19-research&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for Covid-19 research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is desperate to learn the epidemiological factors that influence risk of infection by the SARS-CoV-2 virus, and severity of ensuing Covid-19 disease. As a consequence, data is being gathered rapidly and in many different contexts to answer these questions - but the non-random manner in which data is being collected opens up problems in causal inference and prediction models. I am leading an effort to understand these biases and to develop tools to counteract them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decolonising-the-curriculum&#34;&gt;Decolonising the curriculum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of a curriculum is to determine what knowledge we value, and it presents a world view to our students. A colonised curriculum is one in which bias relating to coloniality influences that knowledge base, and influences that world view. It has major implications for our students in the medical school, both for clinical practice and for medical research. The premise of decolonisation is that removing these biases will improve outcomes for all (including those who have been excluded and those who have not). I co-lead the Decolonising the curriculum special interest group at the Bristol Medical School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://decolbms.org.uk/&#34;&gt;http://decolbms.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;team&#34;&gt;Team&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current&#34;&gt;Current&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoonsu Cho (Post-doc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clare Horscroft (Post-doc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sam Neaves (Post-doc, data manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hannah Wilson (PhD student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lily Andrews (PhD student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amanda Forde (PhD student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Moreno-Stokoe (PhD student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;former&#34;&gt;Former&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ildar Sadreev (Post-doc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Battram (PhD student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laurence Howe (PhD student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charles Laurin (Post-doc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aidan Ball (MSc student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;available-positions&#34;&gt;Available positions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am always interested in working with talented individuals in any areas of research described above. Please email me with questions about available positions and current projects if you are interested in working with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My personal github page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer&#34;&gt;https://github.com/explodecomputer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also regularly contribute to the MRC IEU github organisation code base: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrcieu/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mrcieu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;causal-inference&#34;&gt;Causal inference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcieu.github.io/TwoSampleMR/&#34;&gt;TwoSampleMR R package&lt;/a&gt; - Methods for two-sample Mendelian randomization, along with data management and harmonisation functions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://app.mrbase.org/&#34;&gt;MR-Base web app&lt;/a&gt; - Simple wrapper for the TwoSampleMR R package&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explodecomputer.github.io/tryx/index.html&#34;&gt;MR-TRYX R package&lt;/a&gt; - Detecting novel pathways to disease by exploiting horizontal pleiotropy (TReasure Your eXceptions!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;genetics&#34;&gt;Genetics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gwas-api.mrcieu.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;OpenGWAS API&lt;/a&gt; - Rapidly query across hundreds of billions of genetic associations, and perform related LD-based operations such as clumping and identifying tagging variants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcieu.github.io/ieugwasr/&#34;&gt;ieugwasr R package&lt;/a&gt; - A simple R interface for convenient access to the OpenGWAS API&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcieu.github.io/gwasvcf/&#34;&gt;gwasvcf R package&lt;/a&gt; - Rapidly query genetic associations in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.05.29.115824v1&#34;&gt;GWAS VCF file format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcieu.github.io/gwasglue/&#34;&gt;gwasglue R package&lt;/a&gt; - Connect data from GWAS VCF files or the OpenGWAS API to a range of analytical tools designed for GWAS summary data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://api.godmc.org.uk/v0.1&#34;&gt;GoDMC API&lt;/a&gt; - Query the cis- and trans-mQTL results from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://godmc.org.uk/&#34;&gt;GoDMC project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/random-metal&#34;&gt;random-METAL&lt;/a&gt; - An edit to the popular software package &lt;a href=&#34;https://genome.sph.umich.edu/wiki/METAL&#34;&gt;METAL&lt;/a&gt;. This edit enables a DerSimonian-Laird random effects meta-analysis model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://explodecomputer.github.io/simulateGP/&#34;&gt;simulateGP&lt;/a&gt; - R package that contains a collection of methods for simulating and analysing genotype-phenotype relationships&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/imputePipe&#34;&gt;ImputePipe&lt;/a&gt; - Pipelines for performing imputation of genotyped datasets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.cnsgenomics.com/gctaPower/&#34;&gt;gctaPower&lt;/a&gt; - Power calculator for univariate and bivariate genomic REML analyses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/epiGPU&#34;&gt;epiGPU&lt;/a&gt; - Perform exhaustive two-dimensional epistasis scans rapidly using GPU accelerators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/episcan&#34;&gt;epiCPU&lt;/a&gt; - Perform exhaustive two-dimensional epistasis scans rapidly across multiple CPU cores&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/epipower&#34;&gt;epiPower web app&lt;/a&gt; - Calculate statistical power and significance thresholds for two-dimensional epistasis scans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epidemiology&#34;&gt;Epidemiology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/AscRtain&#34;&gt;ascRtain R package&lt;/a&gt; - Explore bias in observational associations due to collider issues that arise from non-random sampling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://variables.alspac.bris.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;ALSPAC data dictionary&lt;/a&gt; - Browse all the phenotypic variables captured within the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bristol.ac.uk/alspac/&#34;&gt;Avon Longitudinal Study for Parents and Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;random-stuff&#34;&gt;Random stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uss-pension-model.com/&#34;&gt;USS Pension model&lt;/a&gt; - Collaboration with Neil Davies to illustrate the impact of the planned changes to the UK University pension scheme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/shared-parental-leave&#34;&gt;Shared parental leave calculator&lt;/a&gt; - How to divide up shared parental leave? This R package attempts to calculate the cost, time spent with baby and work time lost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2022&#34;&gt;2022&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Mendelian randomisation to detect causal influences of molecular features on complex traits&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk to the Broad Institute (Harvard and MIT) methods seminar series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The MR-Base and OpenGWAS projects&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk to BenevolentAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decolonising the Bristol Medical School curriculums&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk at the BILT Compassionate Conference &lt;a href=&#34;https://bilt.online/the-compassionate-conference/&#34;&gt;[video]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contemporary Genome Wide Association Study findings in the light of Mendelian inheritance&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk at the Mendel @ 200 conference, Bristol &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NZweqJIBODI&#34;&gt;[video]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring the assumptions in Mendelian randomisation&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk to the Cure Huntington&amp;rsquo;s Disease Initiative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2021&#34;&gt;2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mendelian randomisation for molecular exposures&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk to GSK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Mendelian randomisation to detect causal influences of molecular features on complex traits&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk for Channing Network seminar series, Harvard University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2020&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New data on Covid-19 is undermined by old statistical problems&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk as part of the Elizabeth Blackwell Institute data week programme [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVQsFziZ83g&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/new-data-on-covid-19-is-undermined-by-old-statistical-problems-tickets-105058540924&#34;&gt;eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEGEG meeting in Bristol 2019&lt;/strong&gt; - Hosted the South England Genetic Epidemiology Group meeting at the Watershed Cinema, Bristol [&lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.eventbrite.com/e/segeg-meeting-in-bristol-2019-registration-59018859999)&#34;&gt;eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetic architecture&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited chair, 2019 GRC Quantitative Genetics conference, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetics of DNA methylation&lt;/strong&gt; - Plenary, Mendelian Randomization conference, Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advice on applying for fellowships&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk, University of Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automating Mendelian randomization&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk at the SEGEG meeting, Oxford&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine learning in Mendelian randomization&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk at the Edinburgh Alliance in Quantitative Genetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Causal inference and machine learning&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk at the Oxford-Man Institute of Quantitative Finance, University of Oxford&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Causal graph of the human phenome&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk at UCL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods in causal inference&lt;/strong&gt; - NIA DGCG Omics Meeting, National Institute on Aging, Washington DC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wellcome Trust public debate on genetic data privacy&lt;/strong&gt; - Panel member, Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution of rare variants to complex traits&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk, NEGEG meeting, Manchester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetic architecture of DNA methylation levels&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk, Northern Epigenetics Club, Manchester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inferring genetic architecture of rare variants&lt;/strong&gt; - Invited talk, Royal Statistical Society meeting on &amp;ldquo;Hidden complexities in complex traits&amp;rdquo;, London&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horizontal pleiotropy in Mendelian randomization&lt;/strong&gt; - Plenary, Mendelian Randomization conference, Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetic architecture of DNA methylation levels&lt;/strong&gt; - Plenary, Epigenomics of Common Disease 2015, Cambridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://www.explodecomputer.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.explodecomputer.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;genomic-data-science-module&#34;&gt;Genomic Data science module&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top medical students at the University of Bristol have an option to intercalate during their third year. I co-lead a 20-credit module as part of the Genomic Medicine iBSc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bristol.ac.uk/medical-school/study/undergraduate/intercalated-genomic-medicine/&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt; [Link to course website]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eepe-short-course-on-genetic-epidemiology&#34;&gt;EEPE short course on Genetic Epidemiology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run a week-long course, with Dave Evans (University of Queensland), each year at the EEPE summer school which is held in a beautiful villa in the hills outside Florence, Italy. Amazing privilege to be able to do this, and thoroughly recommend attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uob-my.sharepoint.com/:u:/g/personal/gh13047_bristol_ac_uk/EVzIFZat-ttBgHHSazXQDeUBsa6v05SXaEnuxRR5P8fong?e=2lNhaU&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt; [2gb download]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wgcac-genetic-analysis-of-population-based-association-studies&#34;&gt;WGCAC genetic analysis of population-based association studies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invited to co-lead this course with Heather Cordell (University of Newcastle) and Andrew Morris (University of Manchester), each year at the Wellcome Genome Campus in Cambridge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/explodecomputer/MR-lecture-practical&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt; [Github page]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-regular-teaching-contributions&#34;&gt;Other regular teaching contributions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behavioural genetics lecture block to Psychology BSc students at University of Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genetic epidemiology short course, University of Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mendelian randomisation short course, University of Bristol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
